Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928-1984 (Box 217-256)
  - Vietnam
    - General
      Correspondence (including letters to Jim Wright, Graham Martin, McGeorge Bundy, Ellsworth Bunker, a letter from Mike Mansfield to William Fulbright, and one from Nguyen Van Thieu to Richard Nixon), reports (including a report by Dr. Judd to Lyndon Johnson and William Bundy relating to a trip to Vietnam in 1967), printed articles (including David Halberstam and Maxwell Taylor), resolutions, speeches and statements (including Lyndon Johnson, Elbridge Durbrow, Dwight Eisenhower, Richard Nixon, Ellsworth Bunker, Arleigh Burke, Thomas Dodd, Hiram Fong, and John Tower), broadcast transcripts, memoranda, an interview (Nguyen Van Thieu), pamphlets, newsletters, serial issues, bibliography, chronology, book reviews, leaflets, flyers, program statements, and clippings. Includes material relating to the overthrow of Ngo Dinh Diem and peace negotiations.
      - Undated (Box-folder 248: 9)
      - 1954-1962 (Box-folder 248: 10)
      - 1963-1967 (Box-folder 249: 1-5)
      - 1968-1970 (Box-folder 250: 1-5)
      - 1971-1983 (Box-folder 251: 1-4)
    - Pentagon papers, 1971 (Box-folder 251: 5)
    - Prisoners of war, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 251: 6)
      Clippings, flyers, newsletters, and a report.
    - Protests, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 251: 7)
      Newsletters, flyers, printed articles, and clippings. Includes material relating to draft evaders.
    - Refugees, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 251: 8)
      Correspondence, leaflet, newsletters, and program statements. Includes material relating to the National Center for Vietnamese Resettlement.
  - Wallace, Henry A., 1946 (Box-folder 251: 9)
  - Watergate, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 251: 10)
    Speeches and statements (including John Tower), newsletters, clippings, and correspondence (including the Senate Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities).
  - Welfare and social security, 1951-circa 1981 (Box-folder 252: 1)
  - Women, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 252: 2)
    Newsletters, primarily those of Phyllis Schlafly.
  - World Neighbors, Inc.
    Primarily relates to development programs.
    - General, 1951-1982 (Box 253, Box-folder 252: 3-6, Box-folder 254: 1-3)
      Correspondence (including Ramon Magsaysay), minutes, notes, by-laws, clippings, program descriptions, reports, speeches, press releases, and memoranda.
    - Printed material, 1953-circa 1982, undated (Box-folder 254: 4, Box-folder 255: 1-2)
      Flyers, pamphlets, newsletters, and printed articles.
  - World Youth Crusade for Freedom, Inc., 1966-1977 (Box-folder 255: 3-4)
    Correspondence, leaflets, policy statements, reports, and newsletters. Primarily relates to China and student movements. Includes fund-raising letters written by Dr. Judd.
  - World War II, 1941-1973 (Box-folder 256: 1)
    Report, speeches (Franklin Roosevelt), printed articles, clippings, and a press release. Includes material relating to the Yalta and Teheran conferences and to U.S. policy toward the capture of Berlin.
  - Young Americans for Freedom, 1961-1973 (Box-folder 256: 2)
    Correspondence, program statements, pamphlets, and leaflets.
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 1954-1983 (Box-folder 256: 3)
    Minutes, correspondence, and printed material.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1951-1962
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some government records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2010 release of records, 1956-1962 (Reading room Workstation)
    Two reports and a letter. Available as PDF files. The PDF files are page images, so full-text search is not possible.
  - 2011 September release of records, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 256: 5)
    Declassified memo, unclassified memo and letter.
  - 2015 October release of records, 1951-1961, undated (Box-folder 256: 6)
    Includes Committee on Foreign Affairs report summarizing a special study mission to Europe (1951); Committee on Foreign Affairs memorandum of conversation with Ambassador William J. Sebald, Rangoon, Burma (1953); "Minutes of the First Meeting of the U.S. Delegation," Twelfth Session of the General Assembly (1957); excerpt from a House Foreign Affairs Committee hearing transcript (1961); and a "Summary of Programs by Area, Country and Function" for fiscal years 1960-1962 (undated).
  - 2017 release of records, circa 1954-1957 (Reading room Workstation)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1942-1976
  Phonotapes, phonotape cassettes, photographs, phonorecords, and motion picture film. Arranged by form.
  - Phonorecords
    Includes religious material, Just Between Us broadcasts, Dr. Judd's speeches to the Republican National Conventions, debates, interviews, speeches and statements by Dwight Eisenhower, Richard Nixon, Barry Goldwater, Nelson Rockefeller, and Everett Dirksen, reports relating to trips by Dwight Eisenhower and Nikita Khrushchev, and Dr. Judd speaking on communism.
    - Campus Crusade for Christ, "The Uniqueness of Jesus,", undated (Box-folder 256: 4)
      Commercial 7" disc published by Campus Crusade for Christ, Arrowhead Springs, San Bernardino, California.
    - Just Between Us, 35.0 discs (Reading room Workstation)
      Originals in Box/Folder 256: 4
      - 1955 January 6
        Access
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_01
      - 1955 January 8
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_02
      - 1955 January 22
        Use copy reference numbers 85003_256.4_02_03 and 85003_256.4_02_04
      - 1955 January 27
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_05
      - 1955 February 4
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_06
        Communism, airlines, Northwest, Panama, China.
      - 1955 February 8
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_07
        Communism, airlines, Northwest, food to Russia.
      - 1955 February 15
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_08
        Communism, China, Russia.
      - 1955 February 25
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_09
        Communism, Hawaii, Alaska, statehood, trade.
      - 1955 March 4
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_10
        Tax Reduction Bill.
      - 1955 March 11
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_11
        Communism, Eisenhauer, Roosevelt, Military Academy appointments, Fermosa, Pescadores, Phillippines.
      - 1955 March 17
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_12
        Communism, war in Asia, postal pay raise.
      - undated
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_13
        "Judd" written in red grease pencil on disk center. No date, but found between 1955 March 17 and 1955 April 1 within the stack of disks in the envelope. Judd answers questions about the "recently released Yalta papers" (1955 March 16), so this position in the sequence seems reasonable.
      - 1955 April 1
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_14 and 85003_256.4_02_15
        Scope and Contetns note
        Communism, Russia Conference, Yalta, press, disarmament.
      - 1955 April 7
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_16 and 85003_256.4_02_17
        Communism, Betty Fletcher, conference, Chinese students, American prisoners in China, Churchill.
      - 1955 April 22
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_18 and 85003_256.4_02_19
        Communism, Quemoy, Matsu.
      - 1955 April 29
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_20 and 85003_256.4_02_21
        Communism, Diem, Vietnam.
      - 1955 May 5
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_22 and 85003_256.4_02_23
        Farm Bill, price support, Peanut Amendment, milk, Hawaii, Alaska, statehood.
      - 1955 May 12
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_24 and 85003_256.4_02_25
        Marge San Frezus (sp?), Mattie Peterson, Republican National Council of Republican Workshops, Laos, Indochina, civilian operations, peace, security, Hawaii, Alaska, statehood.
      - 1955 May 20
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_26 and 85003_256.4_02_27
        Veterans Administration, universal military training.
      - 1955 May 27
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_28 and 85003_256.4_02_29
      - 1955 June 2
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_30 and 85003_256.4_02_31
        Prisoners of war, death of Dr. Christenson, Saint Olaf's choir.
      - 1955 June 10
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_32 and 85003_256.4_02_33
        Germany, German re-armament.
      - 1955 June 16
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_34 and 85003_256.4_02_35
        Communism, Tito, China, Adenauer, Germany.
      - 1955 June 24
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_36 and 85003_256.4_02_37
        United Nations 10th Anniversary, Korea.
      - 1955 July 1
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_38 and 85003_256.4_02_39
      - 1955 July 8
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_40 and 85003_256.4_02_41
      - 1955 July 15
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_42 and 85003_256.4_02_43
      - 1955 July 22
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_44 and 85003_256.4_02_45
      - 1955 July 28
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_46 and 85003_256.4_02_47
      - 1955 August 5
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_48, 85003_256.4_02_49, 85003_256.4_02_50
      - 1955 August 12
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_52
      - 1955 September 9
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_53 and 85003_256.4_02_54
      - 1955 September 16
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_55 and 85003_256.4_02_56
      - undated
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_02_57 and 85003_256.4_02_58
        No writing on disk center. Was the last disk in the set as found. Judd wishes the audience "a happy new year," implying a date of either the end of 1955 or the start of 1956.
    - 1957 sound recordings (Reading room Workstation)
      - 1957 January 20
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_03_03 and 85003_256.4_03_04
      - 1957 January 27
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_03_01 and 85003_256.4_03_02
      - undated
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_03_05 and 85003_256.4_03_06
      - undated
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_03_07
    - 1960 Keynote Address, Republican Convention (Reading room Workstation)
      - Keynote draft, 2.0 discs
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_04_01, 85003_256.4_04_02, 85003_256.4_04_03
      - First draft of keynote, 3.0 discs
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_04_07, 85003_256.4_04_08, 85003_256.4_04_09
      - Second draft of keynote, 4.0 discs
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_04_10, 85003_256.4_04_11, 85003_256.4_04_12, 85003_256.4_04_13, 85003_256.4_04_14, 85003_256.4_04_15, 85003_256.4_04_16, 85003_256.4_04_17
      - Keynote draft, 1.0 discs
        Use copy reference number: 85003_256.4_04_18, 85003_256.4_04_19
    - Sound recording of Connecticut Republicans Citizens Committee meeting, undated (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002242
      Discs 18-19. Originals in Record Cabinet. Judd speaks about what kind of government is best for America. He says those in attendance are Republicans or lean Republican because the party is the most right on "the most important issue," not singling out what that most important issue is. He speaks on the philosophy of domestic and foreign policies in light of his political history. Though fiercely critical of communists, he reminds the audience that their propaganda is under the promise of helping, liberating people. He accuses these supposed ideas of being lies; that the Soviets are not out for these goals. In the process, Judd speaks on the conflicts between the Soviet Union and China and between the Soviet Union and America. Critiquing the communist standard that one should judge a country purely on physical/material wealth, he says the sense of liberty and personal incentives is the cause of all American successes. He prefers equality of rights than equality of returns. He says the Founding Fathers wanted the government to promote the general welfare, not provide the general welfare. He criticizes the shifting of legislative duties from Congress to the executive, and the growing role of the president from simply faithfully enforcing the laws. Judd finishes by commenting on the actions of the Democratic Party, and why he is a conservative, a label he does not like. Side two of the first disc is a recording of a religious ceremony.
    - Sound recording of the Under Discussion Program panel discussion, 1964 August 13 (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002250
      Discs 20-21. Originals in Record Cabinet. A discussion about NATO, de Gaulle, Europe, and communist countries with panelists Walt W. Rostow, James J. Wadsworth, Walter H. Judd, Robert Strauss, and Francis Wilcox.
    - Sound recording of Walter Judd speech to the Highland Park Presbyterian Church in Dallas, 1960 (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002804
      Originals in Record Cabinet.
      Framing it under the shadow of unimagined technological developments, Judd speaks on the unease throughout the country. He believes this is caused by the clash of two totally different systems--economics, religion, etc. Speaking to a church audience, he focuses on how the atheist communists are different than Americans. Judd believes America should retain its Christian heritage and become even closer to scripture. He shows how Marx's ideas of class warfare and abolition of private property are related to this. He believes the communists want a dictatorship of the proletariat because the proletariats are easy to control. Judd works American foreign policy into this discussion, touching on Israel and China. He finishes by saying one should first be religious, with the pursuit of happiness, prosperity, et cetera coming after that.
    - Sound recording of Walter Judd nominating Harold Stassen at the Republican Convention, 1948 July 29 (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002842
      Judd presents Stassen as someone familiar with the American philosophy, a religious man, and experienced with war. Judd wants Stassen, as new blood in the Republican Party.
    - Sound recording of Walter Judd on the Meet the Press program, undated (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002895
      Judd discusses how America should handle communist China. Judd does not feel America should actively prevent its residents from trading with communist China. He believes America should continue to recognize only Chiang's China and try a Greece-style policy to help China fight communism.
    - Sound recording of the Mike Wallace television program, 1961 August 2 (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002980
      This episode of the Mike Wallace television show has guests Walter Judd, James Burnham, James Warburg, and Gore Vidal. The men debate if the United States should recognize Red China. Topics include what America has lost by not recognizing China, the impact a recognized China would have on Southeast Asia, the United Nations, appeasement, Chiang Kai-shek, Formosa/Taiwan, if China wants to be recognized, and European recognition. Before the debate there is an interview with Dr. Gouchey, who describes a film he made about Red China, concentrating on the role of love and sex in that society. The recording includes period commercials.
    - Sound recording of Stuart Hamblen, the Ravenscroft Male Chorus, and the John Rarig Orchestra performing patriotic songs, undated (Reading room Workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 85003_a_0002983
      The label reads: From U.S.A Unlimited / TV. Production. / Produced by Stanley Lund. /(1) What Can I Do for My Country, (2) America Is A Melody, (3) This Is My Country, (4) The Battle Hymn / Stuart Hamblen and the Ravenscroft Male Chorus and John Rarig Orch...
    - Washington Report on the Air, American Security Council
      - 1964-1965 (Box 257)
      - 1966 (Box 258)
      - 1967 (Box 259)
      - 1968 (Box 260)
  - Phonotapes and phonotape cassettes
    - General, 1959-circa 1968 (Box 260)
      Speeches by others (including Carl Sandburg on Abraham Lincoln) and music (including a Chinese opera).
    - General (Box 261)
    - Speeches by Walter Judd
      - General
        - Undated (Box 261)
        - 1949-1960 (Box 261)
        - 1960-1963 (Box 262)
        - 1963-1965 (Box 263)
        - 1965-circa 1967 (Box 264)
        - 1967-1970 (Box 265)
        - 1970-1976 (Box 266)
      - Washington Report on the Air, American Security Council
        - 1964-1968 June 21 (Box 266)
        - 1968 June 24-November 1 (Box 267)
        - 1968 November 4-1969 March 7 (Box 268)
        - 1969 March 10-July 4 (Box 269)
        - 1969 July 7-October 31 (Box 270)
        - 1969 November 3-1970 February 27 (Box 271)
        - 1970 March 2-June 26 (Box 272)
        - 1970 June 29-October 23 (Box 273)
  - Photographs, circa 1961-1966
    - Album of photographs from the Consultative Assembly of the Council of Europe, Strasbourg, 1951 (Envelope mA)
      Includes pictures of Georges Bidault, Count Carlo Sforza, Paul-Henri Spaak, Paul Reynaud, Winston Churchill, Robert Schuman, Sean McBride, Walter Judd, and others.
    - 9 publicity prints of Ronald and Nancy Reagan, circa 1981; 1 autographed print of Albert Wedemeyer, circa 1982; 1 print of Thomas Dewey, 1948?; 1 print of Harry S. Truman with the Judd family in Rising City, Nebraska, 1943 (Envelope B)
    - 1 print of Dwight Eisenhower, 1952; 1 portrait print of Dwight Eisenhower, 1952; 2 prints of Dr. Judd with Gerald Ford at a FMC luncheon, 1977; 1 print of a White House luncheon, including John and Rober Kennedy, Douglas MacArthur, Lyndon Johnson, and various Congressmen, 1961 (Envelope C)
    - 2 prints (1 duplicate) of General and Madame Chiang Kai-shek (Soong Mei-ling) with accompanying message, 1937-1940; 1 print of Madame Sun Yat-sen (Soong Ching-ling), 1947; 2 prints of members of the National Committee for Christian Leadership of China, 1947; 2 prints of a Catholic mission complex in Shatung under communist control, 1948? (Envelope D)
    - 2 prints of Dr. Judd, with ARCI refugees, 1952; 4 postcards of Laos, 1953; 5 prints of Congressional visitors at an ARCI relocation center, Taiwan, 1954; 8 prints of the inauguration of Syngman Rhee, 1956 (Envelope E)
    - 10 prints of refugees in Hong Kong; 1 print of ARCI refugees; 5 prints of visitors at an AECTR camp; 5 prints of visitors at an AECTR camp; 1 print of a Taiwanese woman; 1 print of a street in the Middle East; 5 prints of Dr. Judd in India with the Dalai Lama, 1957, 1959 (Envelope F)
    - 1 print of a Filipino farmer; 1 print of unidentified children; 11 prints of Dr. Judd and others in Malaysia; 1 print of Dr. Judd and others in Nepal; 1 print of Dr. Judd in Vietnam with Henry Cabot Lodge, Father Raymond Dejaegher, and the Chinese Ambassador to Vietnam, 1962-1963 (Envelope G)
    - 3 prints (1 duplicate) of Dr. Judd in Korea with Park Chung Hee and others, 1963; 4 prints of Dr. Judd with others at a meeting of the Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League conference in the Philippines, 1965; 20 prints of Dr. Judd and others (including General and Mme. Chiang Kai-shek) at a conference of the World Anti-Communist League, Taiwan, 1967; 1 print of priests at the grave of Ngo Dinh Diem, 1970; 2 prints of an unidentified meeting, undated (Envelope H)
    - 4 prints of Dr. Judd with U.S. Navy personnel on Kwajalein (Marshall Islands); 1 print of Dr. Judd and others in Burma; 1 print of Dr. Judd and others in Hong Kong; 7 prints of Dr. Judd and others in India; 14 prints of Dr. Judd with Congressional group and others (including Joseph Alsop), in Indonesia, 1953 (Envelope I)
    - 16 prints of Congressional group at airport and Army facilities (with General Maxwell Taylor) in Korea, 1953 (Envelope J)
    - 26 prints of Dr. Judd and Congressional group in Pakistan, primarily meeting with officials (including Al-Haj Nazimuddin), and touring development projects; 2 prints of Congressional group at a dinner in the Philippines; 1 print of Congressional group with William Donovan in Thailand, 1953 (Envelope K)
    - 85 prints (40 duplicates) of Dr. Judd and Congressional group with officials (including General and Mme. Chiang Kai-shek) and touring development projects in Taiwan, 1953 (Envelope L)
    - 3 prints of Dr. Judd and Congressional group with officials at airport in Afghanistan; 6 prints of Congressional group with officials and sightseeing in Burma; 2 prints of Congressional group in Egypt, riding camels and meting Pres. Gamal Abdel Nasser; 4 prints of Dr. Judd with friends in Hong Kong; 7 prints of Congressional group meeting officials (including Indira Gandhi) and touring development projects in India, 1955 (Envelope M)
    - 4 prints (1 duplicate) of Congressional group meeting with officials in Japan; 3 prints of Congressional group with officials (including Golda Meir and David Ben-Gurion) in Israel, and 1 print of Dr. Judd in a military zone; 1 print of Congressional group with officials in Pakistan; 6 prints of Congressional group with Ramon Magsaysay and other officials in the Philippines; 20 prints of Congressional group meeting officials (including Mme. Chiang and touring a relocation center in Taiwan), 1955 (Envelope N)
    - 7 prints of development projects in Afghanistan; 1 print of Dr. Judd and Congressional group with Admiral H.D. Felt; 1 print of Dr. Judd and Congressional group with Jawaharlal Nehru and Ellsworth Bunker in India; 49 prints of Congressional group sightseeing and meeting with officials (including Sukarno) in Indonesia, 1959 (Envelope O)
    - 4 prints (3 duplicates) of Dr. Judd with John Ondrick and others in Okinawa; 6 prints of Dr. Judd and Congressional party with officials (including King Hussein) in Jordan, 1959 (Envelope P)
    - 37 prints (including 6 duplicates) of Dr. Judd and Congressional group touring development projects and meeting with officials (including Syngman Rhee) in Korea, 1959 (Envelope Q)
    - 5 prints of Congressional group with officials in Pakistan; 75 prints (16 duplicates) of Dr. Judd with officials and touring a medical school, and of a group of unidentified visitors touring a different school in Taiwan, 1959 (Envelope R)
    - 3 prints (1 duplicate) of Dr. Judd and Congressional group in the Philippines; 11 prints (1 duplicate) of Dr. Judd and Congressional group with officials (including Ngo Dinh Diem and Elbridge Durbrow) and others (including Raymond Dejaegher and Hiram Fong) in Vietnam, 1959 (Envelope S)
    - 7 prints of Dr. and Mrs. Judd with officials in India; 8 prints (4 duplicates) of Dr. Judd with the Dalai Lama in India; 7 prints (1 duplicate) of Dr. Judd and others at Teheran airport, Iran, 1961 (Envelope T)
    - 11 prints (1 duplicate) of Dr. Judd with Park Chung Hee and other officials in Korea; 1 print of a building in Korea, and 7 prints of Dr. Judd touring U.S. Army facilities in Korea; 24 prints of Dr. and Mrs. Judd with others in Taiwan; 4 prints of bridge construction on the Saigon River, Vietnam, 1961 (Envelope U)
    - 2 prints of Dr. Judd arriving in Japan; 2 prints of Dr. Judd and friends in Switzerland; 5 prints of pro-Soviet materials and buildings in Brussels; 5 prints (2 duplicates) of Dr. Judd with others and attending a WHO Assembly, Geneva, 1947, 1950 (Envelope V)